<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>toastmasters on Atishay Jain</title><link>https://atishay.me/tags/toastmasters/</link><description>Recent content in toastmasters on Atishay Jain</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</managingEditor><webMaster>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://atishay.me/tags/toastmasters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Meeting Roles and Responsibilities</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/04/21/meeting-roles-and-responsibilities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/04/21/meeting-roles-and-responsibilities/</guid><description>Fellow members. Raise your hand if you have gone through the experience of getting custom tailor made dresses or have seen an arranged marriage. What do you think is common in these experiences with toastmasters. The awkward state of being measured constantly. It is difficult to be the center of attention. You get a feeling that your flaws are getting exaggerated and they will get reported at the end. The thing about custom tailor made clothing and arranged marriages is that, you do it because you need support.</description></item><item><title>Evaluate to motivate</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/04/14/evaluate-to-motivate/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/04/14/evaluate-to-motivate/</guid><description>Evaluation is a major part of a members toastmasters experience. It is a great honor to be an evaluator. Being an evaluator is a responsibility and doing it right is essential for the club to be successful. Evaluations improve our listening and impromptu skills and provide learning opportunities for everyone in the meeting. Raise your hand if you have had evaluations that have had a major impact on your speaking? Raise a hand if you have had underwhelming evaluations where you would desired more feedback.</description></item><item><title>Broadcast yourself</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/30/broadcast-yourself/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/30/broadcast-yourself/</guid><description>Let me introduce you to this gentlemen. Anyone here could guess his name? He has been amongst the top role models on this planet for two decades, the nineties and the two thousands. What was his profession?
Sachin Tendulkar Cricket. It is a game where you would take a break if it rains to continue the next day. A game where after playing for a while, the players would take a tea break.</description></item><item><title>Summer - Table Topics questions</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/15/summer-table-topics-questions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/15/summer-table-topics-questions/</guid><description>Introduction Summer is a very important season. The sun is what provides the life on the planet. Now being the closest to it, in summer we get a lot more energy, sometimes too much that it drains us out. but there are a lot of things we can do in the sun.
Questions Is Air conditioning a good this?
Favorite memory of summer
Which season is more romantic, summer or winter?</description></item><item><title>Table Topics - Daylight Savings Time</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/10/table-topics-daylight-savings-time/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/10/table-topics-daylight-savings-time/</guid><description>Introduction Daylight savings switch in March/November and major events where everyone has to change their clocks. Here are some questions on this theme:
Questions When daylight saving change an hour is repeated or vanishes into thin air. I personally would like the hour that I get my salary repeated. Which hour would you like to repeat on daylight savings change?
Similarly, an hour is lost when daylight switches.</description></item><item><title>Table Topics - A random collection of questions</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/table-topics-a-random-collection-of-questions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/table-topics-a-random-collection-of-questions/</guid><description>Introduction This is a collection of questions that can be used at Table Topics for toastmasters.
Questions What makes humans different from others?
What is the most important thing about you?
What gives you hope?
If God asked you why he should let you into the heaven, what would you say?
What are the changes you want to see in the U.S.?
If you had only 24 hours to live, what would you do?</description></item><item><title>Awards - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/awards-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/awards-table-topics/</guid><description>Introduction Today is award day. We are celebrating all the achievers for this year. And the table topics are also about receiving awards. All of the participants have to come on stage receive the award and say a few words.
Questions Most devoted member
Best table topics
Best icebreaker
Worst speech of the year
Distinguished toastmaster
World Champion of public speaking
Oscar for the best director</description></item><item><title>Tax Season - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/tax-season-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/tax-season-table-topics/</guid><description>Introduction With the start to 2019, we are here at a new tax season. This year with the prolonged shutdown and constant fears of delays from the IRS, tax season has enjoyed more media attention that usual. And many are rushing for them since we don&amp;rsquo;t know if the government will shutdown again. So today&amp;rsquo;s table topics is all about taxes. I will keep the questions simple and hopefully everyone gets to speak.</description></item><item><title>Science of Glossophobia</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/01/05/glossophobia/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/01/05/glossophobia/</guid><description>I have some pamphlets distributed. No need to look at them right now.
According to most studies, people’s number one fear is public speaking. Number two is death. Death is number two. Does that seem right? That means to the average person, if you have to go to a funeral, you’re better off in the casket than doing the eulogy.
This was said by the comedian Jerry Seinfeld in 1993.</description></item><item><title>Democratized Design</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/12/02/design/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/12/02/design/</guid><description>The accompanying presentation is available here.
Fellow Toastmasters. Let talk about design. We are in the information age. Which means we are overloaded with information. And when too much information is there, it is presentation that matters. Bad design is dead design. While we are not designers, the art world has been democratized enough for us to leap from bad to above average just through a 5 minute toastmasters speech.</description></item><item><title>Confessions of a Credit Card-o-holic</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/09/28/confession/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/09/28/confession/</guid><description>This speech is inspired by Jim McDonalds &amp;amp; others from Comedy Time.
How many of you would like to jump of the plane without a parachute?
Just what I thought no one. [If someone raises their hand just call - we have 1/few suicidal person in the room]
How many people here have 5+ credit cards? You folks should buy a parachute.
Madam Toastmaster, My capitalist friends and ever so beautiful judges.</description></item><item><title>New Website and Mailing List</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/09/16/web/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/09/16/web/</guid><description>Mostly impromptu speech on the updates on the new website and mailing lists for Fair Oaks Toastmasters. I don&amp;rsquo;t have this one written and am writing something after the fact that I wanted to speak on.
The presentation is present here
In this speech I introduce the new emails, the new mailing list and the website for Fair Oaks Toastmasters.
This is a follow up from my speech from last week talking about the changes that we did in the mailing lists.</description></item><item><title>Making a non profit more professional</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/09/08/branding/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/09/08/branding/</guid><description>New online identity for Fair Oaks Toastmasters Fair Oaks Toastmasters has had a gargantuan change in its online identity and the team wanted to share th updates with all its members. I have a speech that I gave impromptu to discuss these updates. I don&amp;rsquo;t have this one written but here it is for your enjoyment.
The presentation is present here
The content is mostly youtube&amp;rsquo;s automatic transcription.
Toastmasters is a non-profit.</description></item><item><title>The art and science of Photography</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/07/20/the-art-and-science-of-photography/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/07/20/the-art-and-science-of-photography/</guid><description>Below is an excerpt from a speech that was planned but I changed the topic. Since I had written it down, I had an obligation to share.
{Wear a hat to differentiate an artist}
Hello everyone. Say &amp;lsquo;Cheese&amp;hellip;.&amp;rsquo; {Take a pic}. We all love photographs. Many have SLRs. But do we know how they work and what we can do with them? {pause} I see a few nods. More accessible than ever, camera haven’t changed much from the 10th century dark rooms called Camera Obscura.</description></item><item><title>Bread and Charles Darwin</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/07/15/bread-and-charles-darwin/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/07/15/bread-and-charles-darwin/</guid><description>Now that you’ve enjoyed the hearty meal, I feel comfortable talking about food. It is not like it is 12 PM on a Sunday afternoon and all of you are gearing up to run for lunch. It is not like I will pick up this bread and someone will come up and snatch a quick bit. Looking at this soft piece of bread I am always amazed how mankind discovered the process of making it.</description></item><item><title>Vanity and Vengeance</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/06/24/vanity-and-vengeance/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/06/24/vanity-and-vengeance/</guid><description>Today I am going to share a popular folk lore in India, sung as a ballad with over 16000 verses. The story is historically inaccurate. Historians don&amp;rsquo;t believe in the love story. According to them this was just an arrogant ruler who angered his neighbors and then suffered a shameful defeat from an enemy he had earlier let live. But the folk lore differs, and the story is definitely the one to indulge in.</description></item><item><title>Passwords</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/06/02/passwords/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/06/02/passwords/</guid><description>My challenge today is an entertaining speech with a message on a boring topic - Passwords. So I will start with an exercise. I am going two share with you two passwords and want you remember them both. Try not to write them down - it is a bad practice to write down passwords. The first password is - @t1$#aY123. Directly the popular xkcd comic strip, the second password I want you to remember is correct horse battery staple.</description></item><item><title>Delhi Driving</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/25/delhi-driving/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/25/delhi-driving/</guid><description>How many people here have been to Delhi? You need not be proud of that. Even I am from Delhi. You guys should know what IST is. IST is the only time zone on this planet where the clock hits 10:30 for the 10:00 clock meeting to start. And it is not our fault. The Delhi traffic is unpredictable. If google says it will take 15 minutes to cross a stretch of 2 kilometers, it could take anything from 5 minutes to 5 hours.</description></item><item><title>Powerless</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/11/powerless/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/11/powerless/</guid><description>Friends, do you remember the speeches last week? One of them had a pyramid called Maslow&amp;rsquo;s need hierarchy theory. Does anyone remember the Physiological need - the bottom most part of the pyramid? &amp;hellip;..How about the internet - Does anyone feel the internet is a basic necessity of human life. I am going to challenge your thoughts. How about electricity - the basis for everything. I am going to describe today a day from back in college when I went almost powerless - fighting for the lowest step of the need hierarchy.</description></item><item><title>Spring Time - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/11/spring-time-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/11/spring-time-table-topics/</guid><description>Introduction Welcome to the day light saving day! This change marks the special point when we are in the middle of spring and the plants are growing up for an amazing summer. We will having table topics today around this fabulous season-
Questions What are the three things you love about spring?
What outdoor activities do you enjoy in the spring?
What do you recall about springtime when you were growing up?</description></item><item><title>First Time - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/01/07/first-time-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/01/07/first-time-table-topics/</guid><description>Welcome to 2018! A new year is a great way to mark a checkpoint in your life. It is also the best time remember the last year and the years before that, recalibrate your dreams and head onwards with life.
Introduction With resolutions in the new year, we plan to do some firsts. Everything we do in life always had a first. Indeed, this is the first time I am writing this post.</description></item><item><title>SMART</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/12/10/smart/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/12/10/smart/</guid><description>Here are the contents of my CC#10. Timed right before the new year, this speech explores setting up successful goals and achieving them.
I was looking through my files last week when I fell upon a rusty old document lying there. It was my new year’s resolution from last January. It was not a great sight. Do I look better than Brad Pitt? No. Am I richer than Bill Gates. No.</description></item><item><title>Toastmasters should be banned</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/19/toastmasters-should-be-banned/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/19/toastmasters-should-be-banned/</guid><description>Friends. You know America maintains a list of banned organizations that we as residents are not allowed to join. How many of you think toastmasters should in there? How many are with me on this - toastmasters should be banned. I am surprised. Are you sure&amp;hellip; No one. Do you all think the weapon of public speaking should not be licensed? Well, I need to open your eyes.
Anyone knows this guy?</description></item><item><title>American Culture - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/11/american-culture-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/11/american-culture-table-topics/</guid><description>Welcome to the culture special. America is a melting pot of diverse cultures and the american culture has picked up elements from a lot of them and evolved them into something totally unique and american. Today I will be celebrating the American culture with all of you through multiple questions where you can speak what your heart feels:
Member Questions Blue Jeans, invented by Levi&amp;rsquo;s Strauss in San Francisco is one of the biggest contribution of America to the way the world dresses up.</description></item><item><title>Think this November</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/04/think-this-november/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/04/think-this-november/</guid><description>This is for my CC#09 - Emotional Topic, persuade with power:
Welcome to November. Today i will give you three short stories. You can imagine them better with eyes closed. First is the story of Abdullah. Abdullah is running. Running like there is no end. Running for four hours continuously. The mid-day sun is searing his body. The temperature is in mid 100s. The scorching desert heat has dried him up.</description></item><item><title>Weird Situations in life - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/10/20/weird-situations-in-life-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/10/20/weird-situations-in-life-table-topics/</guid><description>Toastmasters&amp;rsquo; table topics are fun. You are picked up unprepared and told to speak on things you never thought you would speak on. We have been working hard to make it more interesting - getting people to really think on the fly by not letting them tapping into their speeches and past table topics by providing interesting situations to speak about. Here are some sample questions I created for a session I hosted.</description></item><item><title>The gooey stuff inside of your head</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/09/17/the-gooey-stuff-inside-of-your-head/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/09/17/the-gooey-stuff-inside-of-your-head/</guid><description>This speech went with a slide show that you can view here. This one was a very technical topic to be presented to average individuals uninitiated to the world of technology and code. The biggest challenge for ths speech was to get some content across and still make sure everyone understands it.
Aristotle believed, as many of us still do - the heart is the seat of love, kidney is of fear and liver of anger.</description></item><item><title>Free</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/08/20/free/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/08/20/free/</guid><description>This time I have two versions of the speech the initial draft which makes a good read but gets a beating when we get to the understanding and the final one that I delivered.
Initial Draft Introduction before speech: Atishay wants to apologize to all medical professionals. The contents of his speech are partially true and truth hurts.
On April 24, 2010, in White Bear Township, Minnesota, a 68-year-old retiree, Erwin Lingitz was hungry.</description></item><item><title>Indian Schooling</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/04/23/indian-schooling/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/04/23/indian-schooling/</guid><description>Long Long ago there was a princess&amp;hellip;that&amp;rsquo;s the only way Disney taught us to start a story. Anyways, this princess became a queen&amp;hellip;and what a queen&amp;hellip; the queen that the modern feminists would be jealous of&amp;hellip; The day she sneezed the world stock market fell 100 points. Her laughter was a boost of a hundred and when she got angry&amp;hellip;. Let’s not talk about that&amp;hellip;. I know what {audience member} is thinking.</description></item><item><title>A journey through heaven</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/02/19/a-journey-through-heaven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/02/19/a-journey-through-heaven/</guid><description>Imagine a huge beautiful lake with crystal clear water you could drink. Add an island in the middle that can be accessed via a passage made of ice. No motorboats, no sailboats, not even a wooden plank. To all that add a huge swath of land with lush green grass that extends to as long as the eyes can see. Mountains colored red and yellow with flowers sitting at the horizon.</description></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/01/29/now/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/01/29/now/</guid><description>I have a question to start with - Anyone here prefers 5 million dollars 5 years from now over a million right now? What about 10 million in ten years? How about 20 in 20? 100 million in 100 years. Yes. That is what I want to say - there is a time value of money but it is not as huge as is the life value of money. Now is more important than 10 years from now.</description></item><item><title>Games are good</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2016/11/20/games-are-good/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2016/11/20/games-are-good/</guid><description>Here is another speech for toastmasters, CC#02. I vouch for games - Computer Games that have been cursed by parents for little apparent reason.
Mom&amp;rsquo;s always like to complain.
Stone age moms - Why do you always go out to play? You&amp;rsquo;ll get yourself killed.
Nineteenth century moms - Go out and play. What&amp;rsquo;s there in these stupid books.
Twentieth century moms - You&amp;rsquo;re turning into idiots in front of the idiot box.</description></item><item><title>Déjà vu</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2016/11/12/d%C3%A9j%C3%A0-vu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2016/11/12/d%C3%A9j%C3%A0-vu/</guid><description>Here are the contents from my first speech at toastmasters. This one is for the CC Manual (CC#01). I did get the ice breaker and the best speech of the day ribbon for this. I know if you read this, your first speech is coming up. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry. I have a tip for you. Bind your story in a theme, like I have done with Déjà Vu. This gives something for the audience to remember and also gives you pointers to remember what to say next.</description></item></channel></rss>