<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tabletopic on Atishay Jain</title><link>https://atishay.me/tags/tabletopic/</link><description>Recent content in tabletopic on Atishay Jain</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><managingEditor>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</managingEditor><webMaster>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://atishay.me/tags/tabletopic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Summer - Table Topics questions</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/15/summer-table-topics-questions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/15/summer-table-topics-questions/</guid><description>Introduction Summer is a very important season. The sun is what provides the life on the planet. Now being the closest to it, in summer we get a lot more energy, sometimes too much that it drains us out. but there are a lot of things we can do in the sun.
Questions Is Air conditioning a good this?
Favorite memory of summer
Which season is more romantic, summer or winter?</description></item><item><title>Table Topics - Daylight Savings Time</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/10/table-topics-daylight-savings-time/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/03/10/table-topics-daylight-savings-time/</guid><description>Introduction Daylight savings switch in March/November and major events where everyone has to change their clocks. Here are some questions on this theme:
Questions When daylight saving change an hour is repeated or vanishes into thin air. I personally would like the hour that I get my salary repeated. Which hour would you like to repeat on daylight savings change?
Similarly, an hour is lost when daylight switches.</description></item><item><title>Table Topics - A random collection of questions</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/table-topics-a-random-collection-of-questions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/table-topics-a-random-collection-of-questions/</guid><description>Introduction This is a collection of questions that can be used at Table Topics for toastmasters.
Questions What makes humans different from others?
What is the most important thing about you?
What gives you hope?
If God asked you why he should let you into the heaven, what would you say?
What are the changes you want to see in the U.S.?
If you had only 24 hours to live, what would you do?</description></item><item><title>Awards - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/awards-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/awards-table-topics/</guid><description>Introduction Today is award day. We are celebrating all the achievers for this year. And the table topics are also about receiving awards. All of the participants have to come on stage receive the award and say a few words.
Questions Most devoted member
Best table topics
Best icebreaker
Worst speech of the year
Distinguished toastmaster
World Champion of public speaking
Oscar for the best director</description></item><item><title>Tax Season - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/tax-season-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2019/02/03/tax-season-table-topics/</guid><description>Introduction With the start to 2019, we are here at a new tax season. This year with the prolonged shutdown and constant fears of delays from the IRS, tax season has enjoyed more media attention that usual. And many are rushing for them since we don&amp;rsquo;t know if the government will shutdown again. So today&amp;rsquo;s table topics is all about taxes. I will keep the questions simple and hopefully everyone gets to speak.</description></item><item><title>Spring Time - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/11/spring-time-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/03/11/spring-time-table-topics/</guid><description>Introduction Welcome to the day light saving day! This change marks the special point when we are in the middle of spring and the plants are growing up for an amazing summer. We will having table topics today around this fabulous season-
Questions What are the three things you love about spring?
What outdoor activities do you enjoy in the spring?
What do you recall about springtime when you were growing up?</description></item><item><title>First Time - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/01/07/first-time-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2018/01/07/first-time-table-topics/</guid><description>Welcome to 2018! A new year is a great way to mark a checkpoint in your life. It is also the best time remember the last year and the years before that, recalibrate your dreams and head onwards with life.
Introduction With resolutions in the new year, we plan to do some firsts. Everything we do in life always had a first. Indeed, this is the first time I am writing this post.</description></item><item><title>American Culture - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/11/american-culture-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/11/11/american-culture-table-topics/</guid><description>Welcome to the culture special. America is a melting pot of diverse cultures and the american culture has picked up elements from a lot of them and evolved them into something totally unique and american. Today I will be celebrating the American culture with all of you through multiple questions where you can speak what your heart feels:
Member Questions Blue Jeans, invented by Levi&amp;rsquo;s Strauss in San Francisco is one of the biggest contribution of America to the way the world dresses up.</description></item><item><title>Weird Situations in life - Table Topics</title><link>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/10/20/weird-situations-in-life-table-topics/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@atishay.me (Atishay Jain)</author><guid>https://atishay.me/blog/2017/10/20/weird-situations-in-life-table-topics/</guid><description>Toastmasters&amp;rsquo; table topics are fun. You are picked up unprepared and told to speak on things you never thought you would speak on. We have been working hard to make it more interesting - getting people to really think on the fly by not letting them tapping into their speeches and past table topics by providing interesting situations to speak about. Here are some sample questions I created for a session I hosted.</description></item></channel></rss>